people I've decided to do something
somebody recently asked me to review a
book called the complete guide to
programming and reliable and efficient
programming progo which is an absolute
disaster and I mean yeah you'll learn
something in it but it's it's it covers
all of the wrong things in exactly the
wrong way in my opinion and I am a very
opinion guy I have nothing against
whoever it was that wrote the book I
don't care about that I care about you I
want to help you get through the crap so
what I'm going to do I'm going to commit
to you in 2022 to do because I don't
want to write another book friends you
guys anybody who's been following me
over the last month and a half I've
gotten out of shape writing a book is
hard I would rather educate you and keep
you finding the good books out there and
curating the books so listen to me I
want you to go onto my awesome go
GitHub and like And subscribe to that I
got I'm not grifting here I just want to
be able and this is what I want this
what I'm asking you to do what I'm
asking you to do is to list is to open
issues and I'll create a tag I want you
to open issues on my awesome go site and
I want you to suggest books that you
have found that have been useful or
books that you want reviewed okay and
I'll buy it on my dollars I'll I'll use
you know your streaming money your
contributions whatever I'll use those
that money and I will review the book
and I'll give you my honest opinion of
the book uh if you're like why the hell
should we listen to you
the only thing I can tell you about that
is I've been coding go since 2014 uh
when TJ Hollow Way started coding go as
well gave up node wrote fwell to node
I've been doing it a long time I I'm I
just saved my company $3 million by
writing middleware apis for machine
learning highperformance Computing and
I'm working on my own mentoring and my
own you know projects including Bonsai
um so anyway that's my creds that's my
Flex so you maybe trust me what I'm
going to say about a book when I say I
don't like a book I'm going to tell you
why I don't like the book but here's the
problem I can't give a full review of
this
857 page book because I have to buy it
and and I'm fundamentally against buying
books in general if somebody in the chat
said it why would I buy this book when I
can just go read the standard docks good
question not to mention the fact that it
probably doesn't cover a lot of modern
things so you know but who knows maybe
there's a book out there that is really
worth learning from let me give you an
example some positive things so there's
a book called um what it called
uh I forget it
now head first go so far my absolute
favorite book about go is a book I
cannot rem recommend to you it's called
head first go because the author is
amazing he's really great at how he
presents everything but the book covers
like go 1.9 or something and it's never
been updated and the the somebody told
me that he's he's working on a new book
and I'm really excited for that book um
the bottom line is this is there a 2024
version that get release even more
reason for me to review um I'm a huge
fan of the head first model uh it's it's
a it's a it's a it's a technique for
learning that's grounded in neuroscience
and it's silly but it's silly for a
reason and um uh so I think books with
projects are the way to go if think of C
damn so you know but we need to start
reviewing these books and reviewing
these things and I'm happy to do that
for you I'm going to make it a thing um
yeah the the head first series I learned
ceve from head first SE really truly I
learned about they he been stacked by
reading head firsty um so I mean I'm a
huge fan of the head first series um the
biggest problem with any book of course
is they get so out of date um so you
know this is I don't the only thing you
need to take away from this is if you
have a book that you want me to review
that you're thinking of buy them before
you drop 40 bucks on it don't and let me
tell you why I'm going to end with a
very negative story there's there's a
person who shall remain unnamed who made
a book and go I wanted to learn generics
so I dropped 40 bucks on a book from
packed publishing one of the worst
nothing no book who was at packed
publish every single book from packed
publishing is absolute do not buy
pack publishing I did a whole video
about this but let me hear me out so I
bought this book because I wanted to
learn generics and generics are hard Rob
Pike prefers to call them parameterized
polymorphism which is really great way
to think of it
and and I've since learned them by you
know studying them and writing my own
rooted no trees and Link lists and all
these cool funing things you can all see
them in my bonsai uh my bonsai library
but you know because I needed to learn
generics problem is I bought this book
and it it covered a proposal that wasn't
even close to being final and I learned
it I learned generics by using this
completely wrong
proposal I paid the money I actually
bought two copies of the book a Kindle
one and that one it wasn't until I got
through the book and I got through the
whole thing that I realized later on
that it had nothing to do with reality
you know what they did they released
another book and said get our updated
book and they charged another $40 and
the hubris to charge more money without
ever even saying that the other book had
problems in it we didn't say our book
accurately covered generics it says
right here that it's just a proposal
blah blah blah no it wasn't even close
to what ended up being final I had to
relearn the whole thing and I'm mad
about it to this day I'm mad I'm mad at
myself s for not reading the fine print
if it was there and for letting it
happen so don't get mad get busy and in
this case I'm maybe going to save you
from pain and suffering by doing that
kind of thing now certainly you can do
that kind of evaluation for yourself but
but if it's more fun and we can do it
together what I'm asking you to do once
again go out to my awesome go to my
awesome go repo it's like one read me
and tell me open issues about the books
you want me to review and I will go in
there and we will close those issues off
and we will make a review and we'll do
an exhausted review and I'll buy the
book I'll buy it I'll buy the book and I
will say okay let's go look at this and
see what's wrong with it to I tell you
what though if I read through something
if I read something in the in the Amazon
thing and I can see what's in the book
and I know right away it's not going to
cover something I'm going to be like no
I'm not wasting money on that I am not
even wasting money on the book to even
do a review there are lots of good books
that have a rata in them so like go in
action I reviewed I had to submit an
Arata on it because it this code
wouldn't even compile I'm not even
kidding I absolutely love Kennedy Bill
Kennedy and the people that that and all
the things that they're doing the code
in that book wouldn't even
compile so you know these are things
that you think you would test before you
release the
book so anyway that's an invitation to
you to to help me help you and uh maybe
we can have fun with it maybe maybe we
can just watch me rant and blow my blood
pressure I hopefully the reason I want
to do this is because maybe there's a
really great book out there there might
be a and everybody knows there's like a
plethora of books now would you say I
have a plethora of books on go yeah
before there weren't like any I mean not
any good
ones and so we can do that rev a lot of
the books that you might be recommending
I've already purchased them and I've
already reviewed them including pre pre
pre-ordering the go programming language
from Donovan and carrian that that I had
a a beginner throw at me because I hated
it so bad I'll tell you that story later
too when we do that review I had to I
had to get rid of all 20 of those books
so just because you are a genius and you
can make Unix doesn't mean you can write
a
book I know bye